Working Inventory of the Robert E. Marshak Papers, 1947-1990
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
- Box Q1
  - Second Order Weak Processes and Weak Instruction Cutoff, including: (Box-folder Q1-7)
    - Correspondence to Academician M. V. Keldysh, Lawrence Mitchell.
    - Agenda for meeting of the Advisory Committee in Eastern Europe.
- Box Q2
  - New York Times magazine, Section 6, October 11, 1964. (Box-item Q2-1)
  - AEC Theoretical Proposal, including: (Box-folder Q2-1)
    - Reports, theories, and book listings by Marshak.
  - Pion Production by Polarized Beam of Nucleons, including: (Box-folder Q2-2)
    - Correspondence and reports.
  - Re-Examination of Soviet Scientific Challenge, including: (Box-folder Q2-3)
    - Correspondence to Mrs. John F. Kennedy, Lyndon B. Johnson, and Jerome B. Weisner from Frederick Seitz.
    - Reports.
  - Old correspondence, including: (Box-folder Q2-4)
    - To/from Allan Valentine, George Collins.
    - Reports and notes.
  - Correspondence related to Remarks on Heavy Mesons. (Box-folder Q2-5)
  - Different copies of theories scientifically stated, including: (Box-folder Q2-3)
  - Eleventh Meeting of the Scientific Councikl of the International Centre for Theoretical Physics, November 21-22, 1974. (Box-notebook Q2-4)
  - Tenth Meeting of the Scientific Council of the International Centre for Theoretical Physics, November 22-23, 1973. (Box-notebook Q2-5)
- Box R1
  - Correspondence to/from C. W. de Kiewiet. (Box-folder R1-1)
  - Correspondence to/from Enrico Fermi. (Box-folder R1-2)
  - Correspondence to/from Alan Wallace. (Box-folder R1-3)
  - Correspondence concerning visiting professors. (Box-folder R1-4)
  - Proposals and correspondence concerning the Reports for NET Publications Group. (Box-folder R1-5)
  - REM-Personal, including: (Box-folder R1-6)
    - 1. REM: Correspondence and photos.
    - 2. John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation-correspondence concerning fellowships.
  - Publications of REM. (Box-folder R1-7)
  - REM-Personal, including correspondence. (Box-folder R1-8)
  - Correspondence to/from Dubridge. (Box-folder R1-9)
  - Draft of the Scientific Council of the International Center for Theoretical Physics (ICTP), including correspondence. (Box-folder R1-10)
  - ICTP-11th Meeting, 1974. (Box-folder R1-11)
  - ICTP-Explanatory information about the group. (Box-folder R1-12)
  - REM-Articles and writings. (Box-folder R1-13)
  - Interdepartmental Folder 1: 7 Tapes-Weak Interaction. (Box-folder R1-14)
- Box R2 (Theory of T-S Box)
  - Reports, including: A Status Report on American Science; A Reply to Congressional Critics; Theory of the T-S Box. (Box-folder R2-1)
  - International Scientific Program. (Box-folder R2-2)
  - Reports, including: Transmission of Gamma Rays through Spheres of Scattering Material. (Box-folder R2-3)
  - Properties of Neutron Stars: reports, theories, and research. (Box-folder R2-4)
  - Processings of Weak Interactions, and related topics, 1979. (Box-folder R2-5)
  - Notebook: Proposal for a National Electron Accelerator Laboratory (NEAL). (Box-folder R2-6)
- Box T1
  - Astrophysics I. (Box-folder T1-1)
  - Astrophysics II. (Box-folder T1-2)
  - Eletromagnetic Theory. (Box-folder T1-3)
  - Electromagnetic Theory. (Box-folder T1-4)
- Box T2
  - Mathematics, including: (Box-folder T2-1)
    - Paper written on the Language and the Structure of Mathematics, 1936.
    - Math notes and notebooks.
    - Final exam papers.
  - Neutron Diffusion, including: (Box-folder T2-2)
    - Scientific notes on the Pile Theory.
    - Notes on Black Sphere.
    - F. Lander calculations.
- Box U1
  - Nuclear Physics-Field Theory, including: (Box-folder U1-1)
    - Wigner, E. P.-On the Matricies Which Reduce the Kronector Products of Representations of S. R. Groups.
    - Nuclear physics course.
  - Nuclear Methods in D. E. by Poritsky; The Theory of Plasticity by Prager Hydrodynamics by Richard van Mises and Kurt O. Friedrichs. (Box-folder U1-2)
  - Radar Research: u-Mesons Scattering Research Forbidden B-transitions. (Box-folder U1-3)
- Box U2
  - Statistical Mechanincs, including (Box-folder U2-1)
    - Scientific notes.
    - Advanced dynamics.
- Box V1
  - Articles (non-scientific). (Box-folder V1-1)
  - Berkeley Conference notes, 1986. (Box-folder V1-2)
  - Budgets-notes. (Box-folder V1-3)
  - Bonn Conference-notes. (Box-folder V1-4)
  - City College-article by REM. (Box-folder V1-5)
  - Clark-Kerr Award, including recommendations. (Box-folder V1-6)
  - Class grades. (Box-folder V1-7)
  - Class lectures, including notes and grades. (Box-folder V1-8)
  - Colloquim talks-notes. (Box-folder V1-9)
  - Conferences-notes, program (1983). (Box-folder V1-10)
  - Erice Conference reports, 1983, 1984. (Box-folder V1-11)
  - Fermilab, including talks and correspondence. (Box-folder V1-12)
  - GENG-notes. (Box-folder V1-13)
  - Gibson, J.-notes. (Box-folder V1-14)
  - Global Mission, including articles by REM. (Box-folder V1-15)
  - Honors seminar, including: correspondence to/from Ronald J. Nurse and honors roll. (Box-folder V1-16)
  - Japan (1985), including: approval for travel and a list of participants for the MESON50. (Box-folder V1-17)
  - Lecture notes. (Box-folder V1-18)
  - Lecture notes, including: (Box-folder V1-19)
    - Stora lecture notes.
    - Superstring lecture notes.
    - Veneziano lecture notes.
  - Grenoble lectures. (Box-folder V1-20)
  - Li, X, including notes and articles by Xiaoyuan Li. (Box-folder V1-21)
  - Correspondence from VPI, including William Lavery and John R. Ficenec. (Box-folder V1-22)
  - REM Personal, including correspondence, invitations, itineraries, contacts, and publications. (Box-folder V1-23)
  - Retirement luncheon-letters of regret. (Box-folder V1-24)
  - DOE-articles. (Box-folder V1-25)
  - John J. Carty Medal (1991), including REM CV and data, and correspondence for REM's nomination. (Box-folder V1-26)
  - Fermi Award (1987), including REM CV and data, and correspondence for REM's nomination. (Box-folder V1-27)
  - Fermi Award (1990), including REM CV and data, and correspondence for REM's nomination. (Box-folder V1-28)
  - AAAS Prize, including letters of nomination and appreciation. (Box-folder V1-29)
  - Fermi Award (1992), including REM CV and data, and correspondence for REM's nomination. (Box-folder V1-30)
  - Fermi Award (1993), including nominations. (Box-folder V1-31)
- Box V2
  - "Academic Renewel in the 1970's: Memoirs of a City College President by Robert E. Marshak." (Box-folder V2-1)
  - Mohaparta, R.N., scientific notes. (Box-folder V2-2)
  - New Releases: articles on beginning research on intermediate vetor boson. (Box-folder V2-3)
  - Newspaper clippings, including excerpts from Gorbachev's speech on Chernobyl. (Box-folder V2-4)
  - Notes on papers concerning the Soviet Union, including Soviet science. (Box-folder V2-5)
  - Notes. (Box-folder V2-6)
  - Oppenheimer Prize; Physics Today, September 1982. (Box-folder V2-7)
  - Particle Physics Course, including roll, grades, evaluation forms. (Box-folder V2-8)
  - Class notes, including: (Box-folder V2-9)
    - Nuclear Physics course.
    - Winter 1987.
    - Spring 1987.
  - Physics 6723-class enrollment. (Box-folder V2-10)
  - Particle Theory Group Budget-notes. (Box-folder V2-11)
  - Correspondence to/from D. C. Peasleee concerning n-n oscillations. (Box-folder V2-12)
  - Phi Beta Kappa Lecture: "Science and World Affairs." (Box-folder V2-13)
  - Phi Beta Kappa speech. (Box-folder V2-14)
  - Physics Lectures by Marshak. (Box-folder V2-15)
  - REM Physics Papers: properties of neutron stars. (Box-folder V2-16)
  - Preon Papers-notes and papers on the Three Preon Models. (Box-folder V2-17)
  - Publicity on REM: articles, newspaper clippings, Physics Today (June 1982). (Box-folder V2-18)
  - Research Program of Gordon Pusch. (Box-folder V2-19)
- Box W1
  - Research Problems, including notes and correspondence. (Box-folder W1-1)
  - REM Research Notes. (Box-folder W1-2)
  - Non-preon and So(10) Research Notes. (Box-folder W1-3)
  - Riazuddin Notes. (Box-folder W1-4)
  - REM Referee Comments. (Box-folder W1-5)
  - Correspondence, including: (Box-folder W1-6)
    - 1. From Frank Avignone.
    - 2. From Karl Berkelman (with articles and notes).
    - 3. From R. Casalbuoni, R. Gatto.
    - 4. From Bob Christy.
    - 5. D Correspondence.
    - 6. Fidecaro Meeting.
    - 7. From Don Groom.
    - 8. To/from T. Koboyashi.
    - 9. To/from T. D. Lee, L. Lyons.
    - 10. From Luke Mo.
    - 11. To/from Frank A. Nezrick.
    - 12. Reports, notes, and correspondence relating to the Neutron Oscillation Experiment.
    - 13. Nussinov Notes.
    - 14. From Robert Oppenheimer.
    - 15. From Y. Okamoto.
    - 16. From J. Pasupathy.
    - 17. To/from Norman Ramsey.
    - 18. To/from Jack Sandweiss.
    - 19. From Y. Tosa.
    - 20. To/from Wallenmeyer.
    - 21. From Ping Wang.
    - 22. From N. Yukawg.
    - 23. From Tony Zee.
    - 24. Neutron Oscillation Proposals and Reports, 1985.
  - Correspondence and reports to/from Sakharov. (Box-folder W1-7)
  - Sakharov Documents, including correspondence, threats to, magazine articles. (Box-folder W1-8)
  - Sakharov Documents, including essays by and correspondence about. (Box-folder W1-9)
  - Correspondence from Raj Gandhi and A. Salam. (Box-folder W1-10)
  - Scientific Impact of the Rochester Conference, including talks at Fermilab and notes. (Box-folder W1-11)
  - Photograph of a group of scientists. (Box-folder W1-12)
  - Shelter Island Conference, including notes, essays, and correspondence. (Box-folder W1-13)
  - Shelter Island Conference II, including notes, transparancies, and lectures by REM. (Box-folder W1-14)
  - Speeches by REM. (Box-folder W1-15)
  - Solvay Conference, including correspondence and notes. (Box-folder W1-16)
  - Notes on Supersymmetry. (Box-folder W1-17)
  - REM Talks, including: (Box-folder W1-18)
  - Y. Tosa-Scientific Notes. (Box-folder W1-19)
- Box W2
  - Photograph of International Institute of Physics and Chemistry members. (Object 1)
  - Transparancies. (Box-folder W2-1)
  - Transparencies. (Box-folder W2-2)
  - REM Travel, including receipts, itineraries, and approvals. (Box-folder W2-3)
  - Articles by REM. (Box-folder W2-4)
  - Zhang-notes. (Box-folder W2-5)
  - Program from 1981 conference on Science and Technology Development. (Box-folder W2-6)
  - Corson Report Volumes 1 and 2: Report and appendicies, from the Scientific Communication and National Security. (Box-folder W2-7)
- Box X1
  - Correspondence to Robert A. Corrigan; Association of Urban Univeristies. (Box-folder X1-1)
  - Ben Beherson Report; Chinese American Basic Research Report. (Box-folder X1-2)
  - The Structure of the Standard Model of Particle Interactions, report by REM; Correspondence from Alice Chanler. (Box-folder X1-3)
  - Report: CEBAF and Future Nuclear Physics by Hermann A. Grunder, 1991. (Box-folder X1-4)
  - Correspondence to/from Ronald E. Doel, Herman K. Doswald. (Box-folder X1-5)
  - Correspondence to Robert Eberly. (Box-folder X1-6)
  - Correspondence about the McMaster Center; from E. S. Fradkin. (Box-folder X1-7)
  - Gellhorn Affair; Faxes and correspondence from Jose Garcia. (Box-folder X1-8)
  - Hoover Institution. (Box-folder X1-9)
  - Correspondence to/from Lev Ioffe. (Box-folder X1-10)
  - Correspondence concerning establishment of the JPS Washington Liaison Office. (Box-folder X1-11)
  - Kendall Statement; Correspondence from Kurstedt. (Box-folder X1-12)
  - Correspondence to/from Leon Lederman, Xiaoyuan Li. (Box-folder X1-13)
  - J. Menhra: list of publications, paper, correspondence. (Box-folder X1-14)
  - Nuclear pioneers; Correspondence from Sigvard Eklund, James D. McComas. (Box-folder X1-15)
  - Correspondence to/from Yuko Okamoto, S. Okubo. (Box-folder X1-16)
  - Correspondence to/from M. K. Parida, J. Pasupathy. (Box-folder X1-17)
  - Riazuddin papers, notes, correspondence, and recommendations. (Box-folder X1-18)
  - Correspondence and faxes to/from Riazuddin. (Box-folder X1-19)
  - Correspondence to/from Roper. (Box-folder X1-20)
- Box X2
  - Sakhorov Conference of 1991: list of invited speakers. (Box-folder X2-1)
  - Superconducting Super Collider (SSC): Correspondence to/from Bob Adair, John Warner, Senator Charles Robb, Rich Boucher. (Box-folder X2-2)
  - Correspondence to/from V. Telegdi, etc. (Box-folder X2-3)
  - UDP Fund: Correspondence to/from Provost David Roselle, Assistant Provost James Wolfe, Acting Provost John Perry, etc. (Box-folder X2-4)
  - UDP Fund: Correspondence from G. V. Gibbs. (Box-folder X2-5)
  - Correspondence to Hugh Van Horn. (Box-folder X2-6)
  - World Scientific Probability Company including correspondence to editors Barbara Aman and Kim Tan. (Box-folder X2-7)
  - Envelope 1: Floppy disk for setting index for book; sample index listing. (Object 1)
  - Correspondence from Bruce Wallace, Alvin M. Weinberg. (Box-folder X2-8)
  - Correspondence to/from C. N. Yang and Paco Yndurian. (Box-folder X2-9)
- Box Y
  - Newspaper articles. (Box-folder Y-1)
  - International Foundation for Science: Letters about the organization. (Box-folder Y-2)
  - Correspondence. (Box-folder Y-3)
  - 12 photographs of Nagasaki Torpedo Work and Mitsrihishi Steel; Political correspondence. (Box-folder Y-4)
  - Federation of American Scientists (FAS) correspondence, reports, and by-laws. (Box-folder Y-5)
  - Correspondence to/from Hans Bethe, including materials concerning the Bethe Symposium. (Box-folder Y-6)
  - Chapters 1-10 from a physics book. (Box-folder Y-7)
  - Subject index for book. (Box-folder Y-8)
  - Subject index for book; correspondence. (Box-folder Y-9)
- Box Desktop 1
  - Scientific Notes. (Box-folder Desktop 1-1)
  - Backup Notes. (Box-folder Desktop 1-2)
  - FFF Chapter 10; Backup Notes. (Box-folder Desktop 1-3)
  - FF Chapter 9, REM Backup Notes. (Box-folder Desktop 1-4)
  - CF Chapters 1-4; Notes. (Box-folder Desktop 1-5)
  - FV Chapter 1; Notes. (Box-folder Desktop 1-6)
  - FF Chapter 2; Backup Notes. (Box-folder Desktop 1-7)
  - FV Chapter 3; Notes. (Box-folder Desktop 1-8)
  - FV Chapter 4; Notes. (Box-folder Desktop 1-9)
  - Scientific Notes. (Box-folder Desktop 1-10)
  - Papers written by Y. Nambu. (Box-folder Desktop 1-11)
  - E. S. Fradkin-Notes. (Box-folder Desktop 1-12)
  - F. T. Avignone, III-Information of magazines. (Box-folder Desktop 1-13)
  - F. Stecker-copies from magazines. (Box-folder Desktop 1-14)
  - B. Stech-copies of materials from magazines and books. (Box-folder Desktop 1-15)
  - Papers by G. Staebler. (Box-folder Desktop 1-16)
  - Papers and notes by E. R. Caianiello. (Box-folder Desktop 1-17)
- Box Desktop 2
  - Correspondence and publications. (Box-folder Desktop 2-1)
  - CCNY papers. (Box-folder Desktop 2-2)
  - Box Contaiing REM's book with annotation and correspondence. (Box-item Desktop 2-1)
  - Chapters 1-10 of REM's book. (Box-folder Desktop 2-3)
  - Notebook of scientific notes from Madison Conference. (Box-item Desktop 2-1)
  - Scientific Notes. (Box-folder Desktop 2-4)
  - Scientific Notes. (Box-folder Desktop 2-5)
- Box Desktop 3
  - Scientific Notes and Articles. (Box-folder Desktop 3-1)
  - Scientific Notes; Articles on gravity, cosmology. (Box-folder Desktop 3-2)
  - Papers relating to science notes, travel notes, correspondence, scientists from around the world. (Box-item Desktop 3-1)
  - Photograph-Virginia Tech Observatory, Halley's Comet, January 9, 1986. (Box-item Desktop 3-2)
  - 29 tapes of Weinberger Addresss at Virginia Tech (1986); correspondence from 9/92; lectures from 5/4/87; corrected book chapters.
  - Medal.
  - Assorted papers and rolodex.
- Box Desktop 4
  - International Centre for Theorectical Physics (ICTP) Council Meeting, 1986. (Box-notebook Desktop 4-1)
  - Personal papers.
  - Miscellaneous tape. (Audio Desktop 4-1)
  - Notes, articles, and papers by B. J. Bjorken. (Box-folder Desktop 4-1)
  - Papers and articles by Enrico Fermi. (Box-folder Desktop 4-2)
  - Notebook; Proceedings of the 29th Pugwash Conference on Science and World Affairs (1979); etc.
  - Reports, notes, and research by Riazuddin. (Box-folder Desktop 4-3)
  - Articles and notes by S. G. Rajeev. (Box-folder Desktop 4-4)
  - Notes, articles, and research papers by Y. Oakmoto. (Box-folder Desktop 4-5)
  - Papers submitted to Physics Letters, Physics Review D., Physics Review Letter; Notebook for Proposal for a Dedicated Collider at the Fermi Mational Accelerator Laboratory (1983). (Box-folder Desktop 4-6)
- Box Home 1
  - Projector Tape: Hilton Hotel, NY: Banquet of the International Symposium.
  - Personal papers: Scientific notes, papers, correspondence.
  - Program of the Pundit Club's 150th Meeting (1970); article from The New Yorker. (Box-folder Home 1-1)
  - Correspondence to/from Wolfgang K. H. Panofsky, G. B. Kistiakowsky, others. (Box-folder Home 1-2)
  - Correspondence to/from Rabi. (Box-folder Home 1-3)
  - Correspondence from Eugene Wigner; discussion of agenda for physicists' conference. (Box-folder Home 1-4)
  - Correspondence to/from S. A. Goudsmit, others. (Box-folder Home 1-5)
  - Correspondence to/from Kenneth Keating, others. (Box-folder Home 1-6)
  - Correspondince to/from Eugene Wigner, Arthur Roberts, others. (Box-folder Home 1-7)
  - Scientific notes and papers; nominations for the Wolfe Prize in Physics, 1979. (Box-folder Home 1-8)
  - Scientific Notes. (Box-folder Home 1-9)
  - Paper by Allen Franklin. (Box-folder Home 1-10)
  - Correspondence and paper from Marian S. Rothernberg. (Box-folder Home 1-11)
  - Kiev Conference-Correspondence to C. J. Bakker. (Box-folder Home 1-12)
  - Papers and articles written for the Moscow Conference (1956). (Box-folder Home 1-13)
  - Correspondence from C. J. Bakker. (Box-folder Home 1-14)
  - Correspondence to/from Geoffrey F. Chew, G. Bernardini; Conference Materials, including: (Box-folder Home 1-Box 1)
    - 1. Rochester Conference 3 &4: Programs and correspondence.
    - 2. Rochester Conference 5: Programs and correspondence.
    - 3. Rochester Conference 6: Programs and correspondence.
    - 4. Rochester Conference 7: Programs and correspondence.
    - 5. Rochester Conference 8: Programs and correspondence.
    - 6. Rochester Conference 9: Programs and correspondence.
    - 7. Rochester Conference 10: Programs and correspondence.
    - 8. Proceedings for the 14th International Conference on High-Energy Physics, 1968.
    - 9. Proceedings for the 19th International Conference on High-Energy Physics, 1978.
    - 10. Proceedings for the 25th International Conference on High-Energy Physics, 1970.
    - 11. Proceedings for the 9th International Conference on High-Energy Physics, 1962.
    - 12. Proceedings for the 13th International Conference on High-Energy Physics, 1967.
    - 13. Proceedings for the 17th International Conference on High-Energy Physics, 1974.
    - 14. AIP Conference Proceedings, 1980.
    - 15. Proceedings for the 23rd International Conference on High-Energy Physics.
  - IUPAP Information, including correspondence. (Box-folder Home 1-Box 2)
- Box Home 2
  - Correspondence, papers, articles. (Box-folder Home 2-1)
  - Correspondence and papers on the Universal V-A Theory of Weak Interactions. (Box-folder Home 2-2)
  - Papers: REM-Mehra materials, replacements in Part Three of Weiner's interview. (Box-item Home 2-1)
  - News articles, reports, correspondence. (Box-folder Home 2-3)
  - Sakharov Talk I, 1990. (Box-folder Home 2-4)
  - Sakharov Talk II, 1990. (Box-folder Home 2-5)
- Box Home 3
  - Articles by and about REM; 2 issues of Change (1981, 1982). (Box-folder Home 3-1)
  - Photographs, including Faculty Advisory Selection Committee. (Box-folder Home 3-2)
  - Bohr II: Neils Bohr Symposium (1989), including: (Box-folder Home 3-3)
    - Correspondence to/from Ove Nation, Victor Weisskopf, Sidney Drell.
    - American Academy Follow-up Action.
    - Notes from Sakharov and Yelena Bonner.
    - Agenda for the Neils Bohr Symposium (1989); notes from the American Academy Advisory Committee.
    - Bohr II Symposium: Notes from meeting in Copenhagen (1988); proposals for co-sponsorship of the conference.
    - Bohr II Symposium: prospective new members for the committee; correspondence.
    - Articles, including one by REM ("The Pragmatic Humanism of Bohr, Einstein, and Sakharov."
  - Correspondence, newspaper clippings from 1957. (Box-folder Home 3-4)
  - Nuclear Pioneers program; Princeton conference on Atomic Energy and World Organization (1947); articles by REM; correspondence. (Box-folder Home 3-5)
  - Newspaper articles; FAS newsletter. (Box-folder Home 3-6)
  - Articles by REM, including: Nature of the Soviet Scientific Challenge; Scientific Research in the Soviet Union, and The Rochester Conferences.; newspaper articles. (Box-folder Home 3-7)
  - Newspaper clippings and articles. (Box-folder Home 3-8)
  - Interview with REM by Dr. Charles Weiner, September 19, 1970. (Box-notebook Home 3-1)
  - Interview with REM by Dr. Charles Weiner, September 19, 1970. (Box-notebook Home 3-2)
  - Articles, correspondence, and reports, including: (Box-folder Home 3-9)
    - Articles by/about REM.
    - Correspondence to/from I. D. Rojanski, L. Landau.
    - Copy of program from The USSR Conference on High-Energy Physics; Reporton Personal Contacts with Soviet Scientists at the Conference on High-Energy Physics in Moscow (May 1956), including letter from Victor F. Weisskopf.
- Box Home 4
  - Newsletters, notes. (Box-folder Home 4-1)
  - Memoirs; correspondence, including letters nominating REM for the Enrico Fermi Award. (Box-folder Home 4-2)
  - Articles and reports. (Box-folder Home 4-3)
  - Correspondence and articles. (Box-folder Home 4-4)
  - Newspapers clippings and articles. (Box-folder Home 4-5)
  - Inserts for FC 4. (Box-item Home 4-Tapes 1-2)
  - Science Report-A Radio Presentation, 12th edition. (Box-item Home 4-Record 1)
  - This Atomic World, March 31, April 7, April 14, May 5, May 12, June 4, 1946. (Box-item Home 4-Records 2-23)
- Box Home 5
  - Daedelus, Journal of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, Fall 1990. (Box-item Home 5-Book 1)
  - Daedelus, Journal of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, Winter 1990. (Box-item Home 5-Book 2)
  - Final Report on City College Development Campaign. (Box-folder Home 5-1)
  - Series of Virginia Tech Lectures; articles, 1986. (Box-folder Home 5-2)
  - Correspondence. (Box-folder Home 5-3)
  - Pieces to Write: Texas Q-Sakharaov. (Box-folder Home 5-4)
  - Soviet Rescue Mission. (Box-folder Home 5-5)
  - Memoirs. (Box-folder Home 5-6)
  - Sudarshan Talk. (Box-folder Home 5-7)
  - REM Summary of accomplishments. (Box-folder Home 5-8)
  - Newspaper clippings. (Box-folder Home 5-9)
  - Conferences, agendas. (Box-folder Home 5-10)
  - Notes, transparancies. (Box-folder Home 5-11)
  - 9 issues of: The Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists (July 1992-January 1993); Issues in Science and Technology (Winter 1989-1990-Fall 1990); Science (December 1992); Physics Today (November 1992); Current Science (July 1992). (Box-item Home 5-Magazines)
- Box Floor, 1980 Blacksburg Workshop
  - "Weak Interaction as Probes of Unification," extensive work from the proceedings of a VPI workshop, 1980; correspondence from Janet Manning, George Collins. (Box-item Floor-1)
  - Invitations to participants from VPI; chairmen and speakers; to banquets. (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 1)
  - Articles and papers. (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 2)
  - List of names of the theorists who sent manuscripts; list of those invited; post card replies. (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 3)
  - Preliminary programs and programs for workshop, 1980. (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 4)
  - List of names of participants, including arrivals and departures, lodgings, correspondence from Lynn Kesler. (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 5)
  - Workshop replies. (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 6)
  - Invitations and list of invited participants. (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 7)